# HARRISON MILLER

San Francisco, CA 9546323386 hmaxmiller@gmail.com

hmaxmiller.com

Full-Stack Engineer (3+ years) - React & React Native. Previously a Human-Computer Interaction researcher. Ran his own product development firm in NYC.

Sı	u:	m	n	na	ry
_					,

Fast learner specializing in full-stack JavaScript, technical consulting, and mobile UI/UX design. 3+ years of experience in React, React Native, HTML, and CSS, with desire to learn new languages and tools enthusiastically as needed. Demonstrated ability in acquiring business knowledge and using data-driven approaches to product development. Successfully led consulting team of Yale engineers and designers to build mobile applications for small and medium-sized businesses.

Hungry to take on the challenge of a lifetime. Authorized to work in the U.S. for any employer.

#### **Technical Skills**

- JavaScript/ES6/ES7
- React Native
- React
- NodeJS

- Mobile App Development
- Mobile UX Design
- Technical Consulting
- Research Methods

- Microsoft Office
- Sketch
- Waffle.io
- Trello

## Experience

#### 2016 - 2017

Technical Consultant, Full-Stack Engineering (React Native)

## Celena

Led technical assessments and software development for Celena consultancy client projects (https://www.celena.co/#team). Specialty in full-stack JavaScript applications using React, React Native, Redux, and Node.

- Facilitated a data-driven approach to prioritize and implement front-end features in the product development cycle for client MVPs.
- Spearhead the implementation of web and mobile applications based on functional, design, and technical specifications.
- Supervise and manage performance of team of designers, engineers, and contractors focused on optimizing service to client base.

#### 2014 - 2016

Developer & UX Researcher

#### Various Early Stage Companies

Received \$10000 in fellowships to build out MVPs for early stage student ventures using React, React Native, NodeJS, Firebase. Projects include Venture (collegiate activities-based social networking mobile app), Membra (public speaking anxiety solution), and Celestrix (VR archery training simulator).

- Execute MVP development based on user feedback and market analysis, often with completion in under 4 months.
- Executed on full product design cycle by defining product requirements, creating user flow diagrams, and producing high-fidelity prototypes.
- Collaborated with an engineering team by leading biweekly development sprints as well as conducting full QA assessments of each release.
- Defined and monitored product usage KPIs to inform subsequent product iterations.

#### Faithlife Corporation

I chose this internship in particular because it provided some unique opportunities to learn about text mining, NLP, and sales engineering. Worked extensively with isomorphic JS tools (React, Express, Flux pattern).

- Designed and built an internal tool for remote sales quoting, in order to solve problem of painful latency bottlenecks
- Gained significant experience with microservices architecture, isomorphic JavaScript frameworks, and Express APIs
- Worked closely with commerce PMs and sales staff tobuild internal quote-to-cash tool
- Implemented, tested, and shipped the tool, allowing the commerce team to close sales 60% faster
- Presented these speedups before a 2000+ audience at the company Demo Day conference in July 2015

#### 2014 - 2015 Front-End Engineer

Yale University

- Designed, built, and optimized author website for Stephen S. Roach, former Chief Economist & Chairman of Morgan Stanley Asia, to promote new book (Unbalanced: The Codependency of America and China).
- Increased site traffic and conversion KPI's for book purchases with targeted SEO strategies.
- Implemented and maintained search functionality based on timsort & Rabin-Karp string matching for database of 100+ op-ed articles.

## Education

## 2012 - 2017 Bachelor of Arts

Yale University

Joint Psychology with Computer Science program focusing on *Human-Computer Interaction*. Read thesis here: https://www.hmaxmiller.com/HumorEvaluationsHCI.pdf

# Community Involvement

- Yale Entrepreneurial Institute Venture Creation Program, \$2500 Fellowship
- National Society of Black Engineers Elected Member, Yale University Chapter
- YHack Hackathon Event Organizer (1500+ hackers)
- Research Fellowships \$5000 Miller Lab Fellowship, \$1000 Richter Fellowship, \$1000 Babcock Fellowship

#### Activities

- Yale University Archery Team Founder & Captain: fundraised over \$7500, hired nationally certified coach, recruited fellow officers, and regulated budget operations for equipment and competition expenses.
- Yspaniola Volunteered to build education infrastructure for communities in Batey Libertad, Dominican Republic.